<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning | Kayla Cummings</title>
    <link>https://kscummings.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://kscummings.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>machine learning</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 17:54:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:square]</url>
      <title>machine learning</title>
      <link>https://kscummings.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Somebody poisoned the waterhole!</title>
      <link>https://kscummings.github.io/project/interdiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 17:54:03 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kscummings.github.io/project/interdiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a summer 2018 SULI intern at Oak Ridge National Laboratory, I simulated synthetic cyber-attacks on water distribution systems with naïve augmentations of sensor data. Then I performed deep transfer learning on synthetic-attack data to detect real cyber-attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two graduate projects extend my previous work by first replacing the naïve attack engine with deep learning, then with network interdiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deliverable downloads:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;ornl_poster.pdf&#34; download&gt;ORNL poster&lt;/a&gt;, cleared for external circulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;6_883.pdf&#34; download&gt;Deep learning report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;1_208.pdf&#34; download&gt;Network interdiction report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6883-modeling-with-machine-learning&#34;&gt;6.883 Modeling with Machine Learning:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Algorithms to Applications
&lt;em&gt;Spring 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my final project for this course, I built an adversarial variational autoencoder (VAE) to generate synthetic attacks. The adversarial VAE variant includes a second neural network branch from the latent space whose task is to classify the reconstructed sensor readings as clean or compromised. The loss function is a linear combination of KL-divergence and binary cross-entropy to enforce smooth and clustered encoding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;vae.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach achieved slight attack detection improvement over the naïve engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1208-resilient-networks&#34;&gt;1.208 Resilient Networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this course&amp;rsquo;s final project I turned to network interdiction models to add domain-specific knowledge for synthetic attack generation. I used network interdiction outcomes to identify critical links or network components which an attacker might target to maximize the effect of a single cyber-layer interference. These targeted links were translated into a distribution over the water distribution network&amp;rsquo;s cyber components. I used this distribution to model a potential adversary&amp;rsquo;s topological priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;translation.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generated synthetic attacks over the cyber components proportionally to the simulated component priority distributions.
The results indicated that topology-informed synthetic attacks enable more sensitive, more specific, and less paranoid detection of true cyber-attacks than the topology-agnostic attack engines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Liver and You Learn</title>
      <link>https://kscummings.github.io/project/livers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 17:43:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kscummings.github.io/project/livers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network (OPTN) is in charge of allocating livers as they arrive to wait-listed candidates.
Consensus among doctors is that a fair policy should prioritize patients whose conditions would deteriorate most quickly without a transplant.
Current practice prioritizes patients who are most likely to die or become medically unfit for transplant within 3 months.

&lt;a href=&#34;https://lids.mit.edu/people/students/sam-gilmour&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sam Gilmour,&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/josh-wilde&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Josh Wilde,&lt;/a&gt;
 and I used machine learning and optimization to explore candidate ranking policies based on projected post-transplant outcomes rather than pre-transplant vitality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deliverables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;liver-poster.pdf&#34;&gt;Poster&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;6_867.pdf&#34;&gt;Final report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6867-machine-learning&#34;&gt;6.867 Machine Learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A policy based on post-transplant outcomes necessarily accounts for organ features as well as patient features.
We formulated a maximum weighted matching model in the lineage of work by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1287/opre.1120.1138&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bertsimas &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

The weights were equal to the gain that the transplant system would receive by matching an organ to a particular patient, quantified by organ acceptance likelihood and projected post-transplant survival.
We further constrained the model by including demographic fairness considerations.
We constructed a Lagrangean relaxation of the fairness constraints to obtain fairness-adjusted weights in a classical matching problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; width=&#34;300\%&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We required a method for which system benefits could be estimated for newly observed patient-organ pairs.
We obtained these estimated benefits as the solutions to a standard OLS regression problem, in which patient and organ features predicted fairness-adjusted weights to the above matching problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We iterated with a dynamic policy that changes according to the patients on the waitlist.
We hypothesized that the fairness-adjusted weights depend on the characteristics of the current patient waitlist and the organs available for transplant.
Our strategy was to predict this dependence by regressing over batch-level organ and patient features to predict one fairness-adjusted weight in the static priority map.
Collectively, the learned parameters formed a dynamic policy map generator that yielded fairness-adjusted weights for a given batch of patients and organs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We built a model that simulates liver allocation and survival outcomes to benchmark the performance of our policies
against existing ranking policies. Simulations showed that our policies resulted in approximately 1%
more transplants and consequently 1% fewer pre-transplant deaths, with minimal effect on post-transplant
morbidity and with continued fair allocation for targeted demographics. Furthermore, our
dynamic policy performed at par with the static policy, indicating that its additional computational
overhead may be unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you sure that goes there?</title>
      <link>https://kscummings.github.io/project/unhcr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kscummings.github.io/project/unhcr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/josh-wilde&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Josh Wilde&lt;/a&gt;
 and I used robust optimization and machine learning to capture emergency demand uncertainty in the joint humanitarian facility location and inventory pre-positioning problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deliverables:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;unhcr_poster.pdf&#34;&gt;Poster&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;15_094.pdf&#34;&gt;Final report&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;15094j-robust-modeling-optimization-and-computation&#34;&gt;15.094J Robust Modeling, Optimization and Computation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spring 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jom.2016.05.009&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jahre &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 model the humanitarian network design problem for the UNHCR as a two-stage stochastic optimization problem. The first stage is a facility location problem, and the second stage is a stock pre-positioning problem that depends on the selected facility locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh and I augmented this work using robust optimization, whose theory seeks decisions that successfully navigate the trade-off between expected optimality and mitigation of parametric uncertainty.
Emergency humanitarian demand can wildly oscillate between negligible and astronomical levels from year to year, distinguishing humanitarian network design from the typical facility location problem.
Because historical demand is consequentially not a reliable indication of future demand, we capture emergency demand uncertainty using machine learning demand forecasts.
We build a robust optimization formulation by embedding these forecasts into uncertainty sets for the emergency demand parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;map.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find that optimal facility locations are agnostic to emergency demand uncertainty, which lends confidence to this more permanent first-stage decision.
Fulfillment costs meaningfully decrease as a result of the incorporation of demand forecasts into uncertainty sets, but inventory allocations are highly paranoid and sensitive to the specific demand forecast.
This conclusion together with the invariant optimal network configuration indicates that the robust demand pre-positioning problem can be divorced from the facility location problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
